<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.kstars.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kstars</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKStarsxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">天文_KStars</name>
  <summary>Desktop Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Stoni planetarij</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Planetari per a l'escriptori</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Planetari per a l'escriptori</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Planetárium na vaší obrazovce</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Elektronisches Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Desktop Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Planetario para el escritorio</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Töölaua planetaarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Työpöytäplanetaario</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Planetario de escritorio</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">데스크톱 별자리판</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Darbalaukio planetariumas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Planetarium för den Schriefdisch</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Planetarium op uw bureaublad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Skrivebordsplanetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Planetarium na pulpicie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Planetário de Ambiente de Trabalho</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Planetário no ambiente de trabalho</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Настольный планетарий</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Planetárium vašej plochy</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Namizni planetarij</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Skrivbordsplanetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Masaüstü Yıldız Evi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Настільний планетарій</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxDesktop Planetariumxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">桌面星象儀</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KStars is free, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software. It provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites. For students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations. For the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe! Included with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El KStars és un programa d'Astronomia lliure, de codi obert i multiplataforma. Proporciona una simulació gràfica precisa del cel nocturn, a qualsevol ubicació de la terra, en qualsevol data i hora. La visualització inclou fins a 100 milions d'estrelles, 13.000 objectes del cel profund, el Sol i la Lluna, i milers de cometes, asteroides, supernoves, i satèl·lits. Pera estudiants i professors, permet velocitats de simulació ajustables per tal de veure fenòmens que transcorren en escales de temps llargues, la calculadora astronòmica per predir conjuncions i molts càlculs astronòmics habituals. Per l'astrònom aficionat, proporciona un planificador d'observacions, una eina de calendari del cel, i un editor de CDV per calcular el camp de visió de l'equip i mostrar-ho. Cerqueu objectes interessants amb l'eina «Què passa aquesta nit», dibuixeu gràfics d'altitud vs. temps per a qualsevol objecte, imprimiu diagrames del cel en alta qualitat, i obtingueu l'accés a molta informació i recursos per ajudar-vos a explorar l'univers! Inclòs amb el KStars hi ha el paquet astrofotogràfic Ekos, una solució completa d'astrofotografia que pot controlar tots els dispositius INDI inclosos nombrosos telescopis, CCD, DSLR, enfocadors, filtres, i molt més. L'Ekos té capacitats d'autoguiatge d'alta precisió, i permet capturar una imatge o múltiples usant el potent gestor de seqüències integrat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El KStars és un programa d'Astronomia lliure, de codi obert i multiplataforma. Proporciona una simulació gràfica precisa del cel nocturn, a qualsevol ubicació de la terra, en qualsevol data i hora. La visualització inclou fins a 100 milions d'estrelles, 13.000 objectes del cel profund, el Sol i la Lluna, i milers de cometes, asteroides, supernoves, i satèl·lits. Pera estudiants i professors, permet velocitats de simulació ajustables per tal de veure fenòmens que transcorren en escales de temps llargues, la calculadora astronòmica per predir conjuncions i molts càlculs astronòmics habituals. Per l'astrònom aficionat, proporciona un planificador d'observacions, una eina de calendari del cel, i un editor de CDV per calcular el camp de visió de l'equip i mostrar-ho. Cerqueu objectes interessants amb l'eina «Què passa esta nit», dibuixeu gràfics d'altitud vs. temps per a qualsevol objecte, imprimiu diagrames del cel en alta qualitat, i obtingueu l'accés a molta informació i recursos per ajudar-vos a explorar l'univers! Inclòs amb el KStars hi ha el paquet astrofotogràfic Ekos, una solució completa d'astrofotografia que pot controlar tots els dispositius INDI inclosos nombrosos telescopis, CCD, DSLR, enfocadors, filtres, i molt més. L'Ekos té capacitats d'autoguiatge d'alta precisió, i permet capturar una imatge o múltiples usant el potent gestor de seqüències integrat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">KStars is free, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software. It provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites. For students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations. For the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe! Included with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">KStars es un software de Astronomía libre, de código abierto y multiplataforma. Proporciona una precisa simulación gráfica del cielo nocturno desde cualquier punto de la Tierra y en cualquier fecha y hora. Puede mostrar hasta 100 millones de estrellas, 13.000 objetos del espacio profundo, los 8 planetas, el Sol, la Luna y miles de cometas, asteroides, supernovas y satélites. Para estudiantes y profesores, permite velocidades de simulación ajustables para poder visualizar los fenómenos que ocurren a lo largo de grandes periodos de tiempo. La calculadora astronómica de KStars se puede usar para predecir conjunciones y para realizar numerosos cálculos astronómicos. Para el astrónomo aficionado, proporciona un planificador de observaciones, una herramienta de calendario celeste y un editor de campo visual para calcular el campo visual de su equipo y mostrarlo. Encuentre objetos interesantes con la herramienta «Qué ocurre esta noche», dibuje gráficos de altura frente a tiempo de cualquier objeto, imprima cartas estelares de gran calidad y obtenga acceso a gran cantidad de información y recursos que le ayudarán a explorar el universo. KStars incluye la suite de astrofotografía Ekos, una completa solución de fotografía astronómica que puede controlar todos los dispositivos INDI, como numerosos telescopios, cámaras CCD y DSLR, sistemas de enfoque, filtros, entre otros. Ekos permite realizar un seguimiento muy preciso mediante el uso de un sistema de identificación astrométrico con o sin conexión a Internet y las posibilidades de enfoque y guiado automáticos. También permite capturar una o varias imágenes mediante el uso de un potente gestor de secuencias integrado.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">KStars on vaba, avatud lähtekoodiga, platvormist sõltumatu astronoomiarakendus. See pakub öise taeva täpset graafilist imitatsiooni mis tahes maakera punktis mis tahes kuupäeval ja kellaajal. Näha on kuni 100 miljonit tähte, 13 000 Päikesesüsteemi välist objekti, kõik 8 planeeti, Kuu ja Päike ning tuhanded komeedid, asteroidid, supernoovad ja satelliidid. Nii õpetajad kui ka õpilased saavad kohandada imitatsiooni kiirust, et näha taevailminguid, mis juhtuvad väga pika aja jooksul. KStarsi astrokalkulaator ennustab ette varjutusi ja võimaldab veel mitmesuguseid tavalisemaid astronoomilisi arvutusi. Amatöörastronoomile on pakkuda vaatluste planeerija, taevakalendri tööriist ja vaatevälja redaktor, mis võimaldab välja arvutada vaatlusseadme vaatevälja ja seda näidata. Huvipakkuvaid objekte leiab "Mis on täna näha" tööriistaga, kõigi objektide ajas muutuvat kõrgust saab lasta üles joonistada, trükkida võib kõrge kvaliteediga taevakaarte, samuti pakutakse ligipääsu suurele hulgale teabele ja ressurssidele, mis lasevad põhjalikult uurida kogu universumit! KStarsiga on kaasa Ekose astrofotograafia komplekt, mis suudab juhtida kõiki INDI seadmeid, sealhulgas arvukaid teleskoope, CCD-sid, digitaalseid peegelkaameraid, fokuseerijaid, filtreid ja paljut muudki. Ekos toetab äärmiselt täpset taevaobjektide jälgimist, kasuades selleks nii võrguühendusega kui ka -ühendusega astromeetrialahendajat, automaatset fokuseerimist ja automaatset gideerimist, ning suudab võimsa sisseehitatud sarivõtte halduriga pildistada tähistaevast kas ühe pildi või sarivõtte haaval.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">KStars é un programa libre de astronomía compatíbel con varias plataformas. Fornece un simulador gráfico exacto do ceo nocturno, desde calquera parte da Terra, en calquera data e hora. A visualización inclúe ata 100 millóns de estrelas, 13.000 obxectos do ceo profundo, os 8 planetas, o Sol, a Lúa, e milleiros de cometas, asteroides, supernovas e satélites. Para estudantes e mestres, o programa permite axustar a velocidade da simulación, para así poden contemplar fenómenos que suceden ao longo de moito tempo, e fornece ademais unha calculadora astronómica que permite predicir aliñamentos e realizar moitos cálculos astronómicos comúns. Para astrónomos afeccionados, KStars fornece un planificador de observacións, unha ferramenta de calendario celestial, e un editor para calcular o campo de visión do equipo e mostralo. Pode descubrir obxectos interesantes mediante a ferramenta «Que pasa esta noite», comparar nunha gráfica a altitude co tempo para calquera obxecto, imprimir cartas celestiais de gran calidade, e acceder a unha morea de información e recursos para axudarche a explorar o universo! KStars inclúe a colección de software de fotografía de astros «Ekos», unha solución completa que pode controlar todos os dispositivos compatíbeis coa biblioteca INDI, incluíndo moitos telescopios, dispositivos de carga acoplada (CCD), cámaras réflex dixitais (DSLR), focalizadores, filtros, e moito máis. Ekos permite facer un seguimento moi certeiro usando software de resolución de astrometría por internet e local, funcionalidades de focalización e guía automática, e captura de unha ou varias imaxes mediante o potente xestor de secuencias integrado.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KStars is vrije, opensource software voor Astronomie, die voor meerdere platforms (typen computers) beschikbaar is. Hiermee kunt u een accurate grafische simulatie verkrijgen van de nachtelijke hemel, voor iedere locatie op aarde, en voor elk tijdstip. Er worden tot 100 miljoen sterren weergegeven, 13000 deep-sky objecten, alle 8 planeten, de zon en de maan, en duizenden kometen, planetoïden, supernova's en satellieten. Leerlingen en hun leraren kunnen de simulatiesnelheid variëren, zodat gebeurtenissen die een lange tijd in beslag nemen, kunnen worden bekeken. Verder bevat KStars een Astrorekenmachine voor het voorspellen van conjuncties (samenstanden), en voor vele andere astronomische berekeningen. Voor de amateur astronoom is er een waarnemingenplanner, een hemelagenda, en een bewerkingsprogramma (editor) voor het gezichtsveld, waarmee het gezichtsveld van de apparatuur kan worden berekend en getoond. Ga na welke interessante objecten er te zien zijn met het hulpmiddel "Wat is er vanavond te zien", plot voor elk object een grafiek van de hoogte als functie van de tijd, druk hemelkaarten met hoge kwaliteit af, en verkrijg toegang tot een schat aan informatie, om u te helpen bij het onderzoeken van het heelal! Bij KStars inbegrepen is de suite voor astrofotografie van Ekos, een compleet programma voor astrofotografie, waarmee u alle INDI-apparaten kunt besturen, waaronder tal van telescopen, CCD's, DSLR's, focusers, filters, en nog veel meer. Met Ekos kunt u zeer nauwkeurig sterren volgen, gebruik makend van een online en offline oplosser voor astrometrie, het heeft mogelijkheden voor autofocus en autovolgen, en het opnemen van enkele of meerdere afbeeldingen met behulp van de krachtige ingebouwde "sequence manager" (beheerprogramma voor rijen (afbeeldingen)).</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KStars jest darmowym, otwarto-źródłowym, wieloplatformowym oprogramowaniem astronomicznym. Dostarcza dokładnej symulacji nocnego nieba, w dowolnym miejscu na Ziemi, dla dowolnego dnia i czasu. Potrafi wyświetlić 100 milionów gwiazd, 13 tysięcy obiektów głębokiego nieba, wszystkie 8 planet, Słońce i Księżyc, a także tysiące komet, asteroid, supernowych oraz satelitów. Dla studentów i nauczycieli, przydatnym okaże się dostosowywanie szybkości symulacji tak, aby można zaobserwować zjawiska dziejące  się w szerokim odstępie czasowym, Astrokalkulator KStars do przewidywania połączeń, oraz wiele powszechnych obliczeń astronomicznych. Dla astronoma amatora, dostępny jest plan obserwacji, narzędzie kalendarza nieba, a także edytor pola widzenia do obliczania i wyświetlania pola widzenia sprzętu. Istnieje możliwość poznawania interesujących obiektów przy użyciu narzędzia "Co dziś na niebie", rysowania wykresów wysokości względem czasu dla dowolnego obiektu oraz drukowania obrazów nieba w wysokiej jakości, jak również uzyskiwanie dostępu do wielu informacji i zasobów pomocnych w poznawaniu wszechświata! Do KStars dołączany jest pakiet Ekos, pełne rozwiązanie astro-fotograficzne, które ma możliwość sterowania urządzeniami INDI uwzględniając w tym liczne teleskopy, matryce CCD, DSLR, układy ogniskujące, filtry oraz wiele innych. Ekos obsługuje wysoce dokładne śledzenie przy użyciu programów internetowych i nie-internetowych rozwiązujących problemy astronomiczne, możliwości samoogniskowania i samonaprowadzania oraz przechwytywania pojedynczych i wielokrotnych obrazów przy użyciu zaawansowanego zarządzania sekwencjami.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KStars é uma aplicação de astronomia gratuita, de código aberto e multi-plataforma. Oferece uma simulação gráfica precisa do céu nocturno, a partir de qualquer posição na Terra, a qualquer data e hora. A apresentação inclui até 100 milhões de estrelas, 13 000 objectos celestes distantes, todos os 8 planetas, o Sol e a Lua, milhares de cometas, asteróides, supernovas e satélites. Para os alunos e professores, suporta velocidades de simulação ajustáveis para poder ver os fenómenos que ocorrem ao longo de períodos de tempo grandes, a Calculadora Astronómica para prever as conjunções e muitos outros cálculos astronómicos comuns. Para o astrónomo amador, oferece um plano de observações, uma ferramenta de calendário celeste e um editor de CDV para calcular o campo de visão do equipamento e apresentá-lo. Descubra objectos interessantes na ferramenta "O Que se Passa Esta Noite", desenhar gráficos de altitude vs. tempo para qualquer objecto, imprimir mapas do céu de alta qualidade e ganhar o acesso a montes de informações e recursos que o ajudam a explorar o universo! Incluído com o KStars vem o pacote de astro-fotografia Ekos, uma solução de astro-fotografia completa que consegue controlar todos os dispositivos INDI, incluindo diversos telescópios, CCD's, DSLR's, sistemas de focagem, filtros, entre outros. O Ekos suporta o seguimento altamente preciso com o sistema de resolução 'offline' Astrometry, as capacidade de focagem e guia automáticas, assim como a captura de imagens individuais ou múltiplas, usando o gestor de sequências poderoso.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KStars é um software de astronomia gratuito, de código aberto e multiplataforma. Oferece uma simulação gráfica precisa do céu noturno, a partir de qualquer posição na Terra, a qualquer data e hora. A apresentação inclui até 100 milhões de estrelas, 13.000 objetos do espaço profundo, todos os 8 planetas, o Sol e a Lua, milhares de cometas, asteroides, supernovas e satélites. Para alunos e professores, tem suporte a velocidades de simulação ajustáveis para poder ver os fenômenos que ocorrem em longos períodos de tempo, a Calculadora Astronômica do KStars para prever as conjunções e muitos outros cálculos astronômicos comuns. Para o astrônomo amador, oferece um plano de observações, uma ferramenta de calendário celeste e um editor de CDV para calcular o campo de visão do equipamento e apresentá-lo. Descubra objetos interessantes na ferramenta "O que acontece esta noite", desenhar gráficos de altitude versus tempo para qualquer objeto, imprimir mapas do céu em alta qualidade e ganhar acesso a uma grande variedade de informações e recursos que o ajudam a explorar o universo! Junto com o KStars vem a suíte de astrofotografia Ekos, uma solução completa de astrofotografia que consegue controlar todos os dispositivos INDI, incluindo diversos telescópios, CCDs, DSLRs, focalizadores, filtros, e muito mais. O Ekos tem suporte ao rastreamento altamente preciso usando o sistema de resolução offline 'astrometry', capacidade de focagem e guia automáticas, assim como a captura de imagens individuais ou múltiplas, usando o poderoso gerenciador de sequências integrado.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Kstars je slobodný, open source, multiplatformový astronomický softvér. Poskytuje presné grafické simulácie nočnej oblohy z ľubovoľného miesta na Zemi, v ľubovoľnom dátume a čase. Zobrazenie zahŕňa do 100 miliónov hviezd, 13000 deep sky objektov, všetkých 8 planét, Slnko a Mesiac a tisíce komét, asteroidov, supernov a satelitov. Pre študentov a učiteľov podporuje nastaviteľnú rýchlosť simulácie na zobrazenie procesov, ktoré prebiehajú počas dlhých časových úsekov, astronomickú kalkulačku na predpovedanie konjunkcií a mnoho bežných astronomických výpočtov. Pre amatérskeho astronóma poskytuje plánovač pozorovaní, nástroj nebeského kalendára a editor FOV na výpočet zorného poľa prístroja a jeho zobrazenie. Nájdite zaujímavé objekty v nástroji "Čo sa dnes deje", nakreslite graf výšky a času pre ľubovoľný objekt, vytlačte vysoko kvalitné grafy oblohy a získajte prístup k mnohým informáciám a zdrojom, ktoré vám pomôžu skúmať vesmír! V KStars je zahrnutý Ekos, astrofotografický balík kompletné astrofotografické riešenie, ktoré dokáže ovládať všetky INDI zariadenia vrátane množstva teleskopov, CCD kamier, DSLR, zameriavače, filtre a omnoho viac. Ekos podporuje vysoko presné sledovanie pomocou online a offline astronomického riešiteľa, schopnosť automatického zamerania a vedenia a zachytávanie jednotlivých alebo viacerých obrázkov pomocou vstavaného správcu sekvencií.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">KStars je prosta, odprtokodna astronomska programska oprema, ki teče na več okoljih. Ponuja natančno grafično simulacijo nočnega neba z vsakega mesta na Zemlji, ob poljubnem času poljubnega dneva. Prikaz vključuje več kot 100 milijonov zvezd, 13.000 objektov globokega neba, vseh 8 planetov, Sonce in Luno, ter na tisoče kometov, asteroidov, supernov in satelitov. Za študente in učitelje so na voljo prilagodljive hitrosti simulacije za ogled fenomenov, ki se zgodijo v daljših časovnih obdobjih, ter zvezdno računalo KStars za napovedovanje konjunkcij ter številne pogoste astronomske izračune. Amaterskemu astronomu ponuja načrtovalnik opazovanja, nebesni koledarček ter urejevalnik vidnega polja za izračun vidnega polja opreme in njihov prikaz. Z orodjem »Kaj je danes na nebu« se lahko pozanimate o zanimivih objektih, izrišete grafikone višine nasproti času za poljuben objekt, natisnete visokokakovostne nebesne karte ter pridobite dostop do velike količine podatkov in virov, ki vam bodo v pomoč pri raziskovanju vesolja! V KStars je vključen tudi Etos, astronomski fotografski paket, popolna rešitev za astrofotografijo, s katero lahko nadzirate vse naprave INDI, vključno s številnimi daljnogledi, CCD-ji, DSLR-ji, ostrilci, filtri, itd. Ekos podpira zelo natančno sledenje z uporabo spletnega in nepovezanega reševalca astrometry.net, zmogljivosti samodejnega ostrenja in sledenja ter zajem posamičnih ali zaporednih slik z zmogljivim vgrajenim upravljalnikom zaporedij.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kstars är fri astronomiprogramvara med öppen källkod för flera plattformar. Den tillhandahåller en noggrann grafisk simulering av natthimlen från vilken plats som helst på jorden, vid godtyckligt datum och tid. Skärmen omfattar upp till 100 miljoner stjärnor, 13 000 avlägsna himmelskroppar, alla åtta planeterna, solen och månen, samt tusentals kometer, asteroider, supernovor och satelliter. Både för elever och lärare stöder den justerbar simuleringshastighet för att kunna visa fenomen som sker över långa tidsrymder, Kstars astronomiräknare för att förutsäga konjunktioner, och många vanliga astronomiska beräkningar. För amatörastronomen tillhandahåller den observationsplanering, en himmelskalender, och en synfältseditor för att beräkna utrustningars synfält och visa dem. Upptäck intressanta objekt i verktyget "Vad händer i natt", rita upp diagram över höjd mot tid för vilket objekt som helst, skriv ut himmelskartor med hög kvalitet, och få tillgång till mängder med information och resurser för att hjälpa till att utforska universum. Ekos-sviten för astrofotografering ingår i Kstars: en fullständig lösning för astrofotografering som kan styra alla INDI-enheter inklusive ett stort antal teleskop, CCD:er, digitala spegelreflexkameror, filter med mera. Ekos stöder följning med hög noggrannhet genom att använda astrometrilösare på nätet eller lokalt, möjlighet till autofokus och automatisk guidning, samt tagning av enstaka eller flera bilder med den kraftfulla, inbyggda, sekvenshanteraren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">KStars özgür, açık kaynak kodlu ve platform bağımsız bir Astronomi Yazılımıdır. Herhangi bir tarih ve saatte, Dünya üzerinde herhangi bir yerden, gece gökyüzünde doğru bir grafik simülasyonu sağlar. Ekran  100 milyon yıldız, 13.000 derin gökyüzü nesnesi, 8 gezegen, Güneş ve Ay ve binlerce kuyruklu yıldız, asteroitler, süpernova ve uydulara içerir. Öğrenciler ve öğretmenler için, uzun zaman dilimlerinde üzerinde meydana olayları görüntülemek için ayarlanabilir simülasyon hızlarını destekler, Kstars Astrocalculator bağlaç tahmin etmek ve birçok ortak astronomik hesaplamaları yapmak için kullanılır. Amatör astronomlar için, bir gözlem planlayıcısı, bir gökyüzü takvim aracı ve ekipman görüş alanını hesaplamak ve bunları görüntülemek için bir FOV düzenleyicisi sağlar. "Bu Gece Neler Olacak" aracıyla ilginç nesneleri keşfedin, herhangi bir nesnenin yükseklik-zaman grafiğini çizin, yüksek çözünürlüklü gökyüzü grafiklerini yazdırın ve evreni keşfetmenize yardımcı olacak bir çok bilgiye ve kaynağa erişim sağlayın! KStars ile birlikte gelen Ekos gökyüzü fotoğrafçılığı paketiyle çeşitli teleskopları, CCD'leri, DSLR'leri, odaklayıcıları, filtreleri ve daha fazla INDI aygıtını kontrol edebilen tam bir gökyüzü fotoğrafçılığı çözümüdür. Ekos çevrim içi ve çevrim dışı atrometri çözümleriyle son derece hassas izlemeleri ve tekli veya çoklu görüntü almayı destekler.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KStars — вільне астрономічне програмне забезпечення із відкритим кодом, здатне працювати на багатьох апаратних та програмних платформах. Програма забезпечує точне графічне відтворення нічного неба з будь-якого місця на земній поверхні довільної дати і часу. Можливий перегляд до 100 мільйонів зірок, 13000 об’єктів віддаленого космосу, усіх восьми планет, Сонця і Місяця, а також тисяч комет, астероїдів, наднових та супутників. Для учнів та учителів передбачено можливість коригування швидкості імітації з метою ознайомлення із тривалими небесними явищами. Астрокалькулятор KStars здатен передбачати сполучення об’єктів, а також виконувати багато типових астрономічних обчислень. Для астрономів-аматорів передбачено засіб планування спостережень, небесний календар та редактор поля зору для обчислення поля зору обладнання та його показу на карті. За допомогою засобу «Цікаві об’єкти» можна спостерігати за найцікавішими небесними явищами. Можна креслити графіки залежності висоти об’єкта від часу, друкувати високоякісні карти зоряного неба і отримувати доступ до значних інформаційних ресурсів, як допоможуть вам у вивченні всесвіту. До складу KStars включено астрографічний комплекс Ekos, повноцінне астрографічне рішення, за допомогою якого можна керувати усіма пристроями INDI, зокрема телескопами, ПЗЗ, цифровими фотокамерами, фокусувальниками, фільтрами тощо. У Ekos передбачено дуже точні механізми стеження на основі зовнішнього та внутрішнього розв’язувача астрометричних задач, можливості автофокусування та автонаведення, а також захоплення одного або декількох зображень за допомогою потужного вбудованого засобу керування захопленням послідовності зображень.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKStars is free, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software. It provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites. For students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations. For the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe! Included with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">KStars 是一套開放源碼，跨平台的天文軟體。它提供全球任何地方，任何日期與時間點夜空精確的圖像模擬。顯示包括超過一億個星體，13,000 個深天空物件，所有八個行星，太陽與月球，還有上千個慧星、小行星、超新星與衛星等等。對學生跟老師來說，它可支援調整模擬速度的功能，以便顯示長時間的星象。KStars 太空計算器可用來預測天體會合，還有許多常用的天文學的計算。對業餘的天文學家來說，它可提供觀察計畫，天體行事曆工具，場域（FOV）編輯器以便計算檢視設備可顯示的範圍。您可以在「今晚有什麼」工具中找到有趣的星體物件，繪出位置與時間圖，印出高品質的天體圖表，並取得豐富的資源與資訊來協助您探索宇宙。KStars 裡並且包含了 Ekos astrophotography 套件，可以用來控制所有的 INDI 裝置，包括多種望遠鏡，CCD 鏡頭，DSLR，聚焦器，過濾器等等。Ekos 支援線上與離線高精確度的追蹤，自動對焦與自動導引，並可擷取單張或多張的影像。</p>
    <p>Astronomical Catalogs:</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Astronomski katalozi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs astronòmics:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs astronòmics:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Astronomické katalogy:</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Astronomische Kataloge:</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Astronomical Catalogues:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Catálogos astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Tähekataloogid:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Tähtitieteelliset luettelot:</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Catálogos astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">천문 카탈로그:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Astronoomsch Katalogen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Astronomische catalogi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Astronomikatalogar:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Katalogi astronomiczne:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Catálogos Astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos astronômicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Астрономические каталоги:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Astronomické katalógy:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Astronomski katalogi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Astronomiska kataloger:</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Astronomik Kataloglar:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Каталоги астрономічних даних:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxAstronomical Catalogs:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">天文類別：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Default catalog consisting of stars to magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Uobičajeni Katalog se sastoji od zvijezda do magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàleg per omissió consistent en estrelles fins a magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàleg per omissió consistent en estrelles fins a magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Standardkatalog mit Sternen bis zur Magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Default catalogue consisting of stars to magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">El catálogo por omisión contiene estrellas hasta la magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Vaikimisi kataloog sisaldab tähti kuni tähesuuruseni 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Oletusluettelo sisältää tähdet suuruusluokkaan 8 saakka</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogo predeterminado composto de estrelas de magnitudes 8 e inferiores.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Standardkataloog mit Steerns bet Magnituud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Standaard catalogus met sterren tot magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Domyślny katalog zawierający gwiazdy wielkości 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogo predefinido que consiste nas estrelas de magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogo padrão que consiste nas estrelas de magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Основной каталог содержит звёзды до 8 величины</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Predvolený katalóg obsahujúci hviezdy do magnitúdy 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Privzeti katalog, ki vsebuje zvezde do magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Standardkatalog som består av stjärnor till magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">8 büyüklüğündeki yıldızlara kadar içeren varsayılan katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">типовий каталог з зірками до зоряної величини 8;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDefault catalog consisting of stars to magnitude 8xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">包含星等 8 的預設類別</li>
      <li>Extra catalogs consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Prošireni katalozi koji se sastoji od 100 milijuna zvijezda u veličini 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs extres consistents en 100 milions d'estrelles fins a magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs extres consistents en 100 milions d'estrelles fins a magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Zusätzliche Kataloge mit 100 Millionen Sternen bis zur Magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Extra catalogues consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Los catálogos adicionales contienen 100 millones de estrellas hasta la magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Lisakataloogid sisaldavad 100 miljonit tähte kuni tähesuuruseni 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Lisäluettelo sisältää 100 miljoonaa tähteä suuruusluokkaan 16 saakka</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogos adicionais con 100 millóns de estrelas de magnitudes ata a 16.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Bito-Katalogen mit 100 Millionen Steerns bet Magnituud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Extra catalogi met 100 miljoen sterren tot magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Ekstra katalogi zawierające 100 milionów gwiazd wielkości 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogos extra que consistem em 100 milhões de estrelas até à magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos adicionais que consistem em 100 milhões de estrelas de magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Дополнительные каталоги содержат 100 миллионов звёзд до 16 величины</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Dodatočné katalógy obsahujúce 100 miliónov hviezd do magnitúdy 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Dodatni katalogi, ki vsebujejo 100 milijonov zvezd do magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Extra kataloger bestående av 100 millioner stjärnor till magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">16 büyüklüğündeki 100 milyon yıldızı içeren ek katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">додаткові каталоги з 100 мільйонами зірок до зоряної величини 16;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxExtra catalogs consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">包含到星等 16 的一億個星體的額外類別</li>
      <li>Downloadable catalogs including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs descarregables que inclouen imatges de Messier, la nebulosa planetària Abell, el catàleg Sharpless</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs descarregables que inclouen imatges de Messier, la nebulosa planetària Abell, el catàleg Sharpless</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Herunterladbare Kataloge einschließlich Messier-Bilder, Abell-Katalog, Sharpless-Katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Downloadable catalogues including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalogue</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Los catálogos que puede descargar contienen imágenes de objetos Messier, Nebulosas planetarias Abell y el Catálogo Sharpless</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Allalaaditavad kataloogid, sealhulgas Messieri pildid, Abelli planetaarudukogud, Sharplessi kataloog</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Ladattavia luetteloita, kuten Messier-kuvat, planetaaristen sumujen Abell-luettelo ja Sharpless-luettelo</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogos dispoñíbeis para descarga entre os que atopará imaxes de Messier, as nebulosas planetarias Abell, ou o catálogo Sharpless.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Te downloaden catalogi met inbegrip van Messier objecten, Abell planetaire nevels, Sharpless Catalogus</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Katalogi do pobrania zawierające obrazy Messier, Mgławicę planetarną Abell, Katalog Sharpless</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogos disponíveis para transferência, incluindo as imagens Messier e as Nebulosas Planetárias Abell</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos disponíveis para transferência, incluindo as imagens Messier, Nebulosas Planetárias Abell e Catálogo Sharpless</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Stiahnuteľné katalógy obsahujúce Messierove obrázky, Abellove planetárne hmloviny, Sharpless Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Katalogi, ki jih je mogoče prejeti in vsebujejo Messierjeve slike, Abellove planetarne meglice in Sharplessov katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Nerladdningsbara kataloger som omfattar Messier-bilder, Abell planetära nebulosor, Sharpless-katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Messier Görüntüleri, Abell Gezegenimsi Bulutsusu ve Sharpless Kataloğu dahil indirilebilir kataloglar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">придатні до отримання каталоги з зображеннями об’єктів каталогу Месьє, каталогу планетарних туманностей Абеля та каталогу Шарплеса;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDownloadable catalogs including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalogxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">可下載的類別，包括 Messier images，Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog 等</li>
      <li>Corrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refraction</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Korekcije za precesiju, njihanje i atmosferske refrakcije</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Correccions per a la precessió, nutació i refracció atmosfèrica</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Correccions per a la precessió, nutació i refracció atmosfèrica</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Korrekturen für Präzession, Nutation und atmosphärische Brechung</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Corrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refraction</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Correcciones de precesión, nutación y refracción atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Pretsessiooni, nutatsiooni ja atmosfääri refraktsiooni korrigeerimine</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Korjaukset presessiolle, nutaatiolle ja ilmakehätaittumiselle</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Correccións de precesión, nutación e refracción atmosférica.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Richten för Küselbewegen, Eerass-Swunken un atmosfeersch Lichtbreken</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Correcties voor precessie, nutatie en atmosferische straalbreking</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Poprawki do precesji, nutacji i załamania atmosferycznego</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Correcções da precessão, nutação e refracção atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correções da precessão, nutação e refração atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Поправки на прецессию, нутацию и атмосферную рефракцию</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Korekcie pre precesiu, nutáciu a atmosférickú refrakciu</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Popravki precesije, nutacije in loma v ozračju</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Korrektion för precession, nutation och atmosfärisk refraktion</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Devinim, nutasyon ve atmosferik kırılma için düzeltmeler</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">виправлення прецесії, нутації та атмосферної рефракції;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCorrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refractionxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">歲差、地軸震動與大氣磨擦修正</li>
      <li>Tools for retrieval of data from online databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Alati za preuzimanje podataka iz mrežnih baza podataka</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Eines per a recuperar dades des d'una base de dades en línia</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Eines per a recuperar dades des d'una base de dades en línia</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Nástroje pro získávání dat z databází online</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Werkzeuge zum Herunterladen von Daten aus Online-Datenbanken</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Tools for retrieval of data from online databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Herramientas de obtención de datos de bases de datos en línea</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Võimalus hankida andmeid võrguandmebaasidest</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Työkalut aineiston hakemiseen verkossa olevista tietokannoista</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Ferramentas para obter datos de bases de datos de internet.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Warktüüch för't Halen vun Daten ut Tokoppel-Datenbanken</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddelen voor het verkrijgen van gegevens uit gegevensbanken vanaf het internet</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Narzędzia do pobierania danych z internetowych baz danych</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ferramentas de obtenção de dados a partir de bases de dados 'online'</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramentas para obtenção de dados dos bancos de dados online</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Инструменты для получения данных из онлайновых баз данных</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Nástroje na získanie všetkých údajov zo všetkých online databáz</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Orodja za pridobivanje podatkov iz spletnih podatkovnih zbirk</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Verktyg för hämtning av data från databaser på nätet</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Çevrimiçi veritabanlarından veri alımı için araçlar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">інструменти для отримання даних з баз даних у інтернеті.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxTools for retrieval of data from online databasesxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">顯示線上資料庫的工具</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/kstars/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kstars</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/kstars/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://edu.kde.org/kstars/screens5.x/kstars_main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://edu.kde.org/kstars/screens5.x/kstars_popup.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://edu.kde.org/kstars/screens5.x/kstars_ekos.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://edu.kde.org/kstars/screens5.x/kstars_observationplanner.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kstars</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
