<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.kstars.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">نجوم‌ك</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਕੇ-ਤਾਰੇ</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kstars</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKStarsxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">天文_KStars</name>
  <summary>Desktop Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">قبّة سماويّة على سطح المكتب</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Stoni planetarij</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Planetari d'escriptori</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Planetari per a l'escriptori</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Planetárium na vaší obrazovce</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Elektronisches Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Desktop Planetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Labortabla Planetario</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Planetario para el escritorio</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Töölaua planetaarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Mahaigaineko planetarioa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Työpöytäplanetaario</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Planétarium de bureau</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Planetario de escritorio</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Planetarium Desktop</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Planetario per il desktop</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">სამუშაო მაგიდის პლანეტარიუმი</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">데스크톱 별자리판</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Darbalaukio planetariumas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Planetarium för den Schriefdisch</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Planetarium op uw bureaublad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Skrivebordsplanetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਡੈਸਕਟਾਪ ਤਾਰੇ-ਗ੍ਰਹਿ ਦੇਖਣ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Planetarium na pulpicie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Planetário de Ambiente de Trabalho</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Planetário no ambiente de trabalho</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Настольный планетарий</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Planetárium vašej plochy</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Namizni planetarij</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Skrivbordsplanetarium</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Masaüstü Gezegenevi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Настільний планетарій</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxDesktop Planetariumxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">桌面天文观测软件</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">桌面星象儀</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KStars is freely licensed, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software by KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">«نجوم‌ك» هي برمجيّة مجّانيّة ومفتوحة المصدر مختصّة بعلوم الفلك، وتتوفّر على مختلف المنصّات.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El KStars és un programari d'astronomia de llicència lliure, codi obert i multiplataforma, creat per la comunitat KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">KStars és un programari d'astronomia de llicència lliure, codi obert i multiplataforma, creat per la comunitat KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">KStars ist eine frei lizenzierte, quelloffene, plattformübergreifende Astronomiesoftware von KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">KStars is freely licensed, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software by KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">KStars estas libere licencita, malfermkoda, plurplatforma Astronomia Programaro de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">KStars es un software astronómico de licencia libre, de código abierto y multiplataforma, creado por KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">KStars on KDE loodud vaba litsentsiga avatud lähtekoodiga platvormiülene astronoomiatarkvara.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">KStars lizentzia askeko, sorburu irekiko, plataforma-anitzerako KDEk egindako astronomia softwarea da.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">KStar est un logiciel d'astronomie sous licence libre, « Open Source » et multiplateforme de KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">KStars é un software de astronomía libre, de código aberto e compatíbel con múltiple plataformas creado por KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">KStars adalah Software Astronomi yang terlisensi secara bebas, sumber terbuka, lintas platform oleh KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">KStars è un software di astronomia multi-piattaforma con licenza gratuita ed open source della comunità KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KStars is een opensource Astronomieprogramma van KDE, met een vrije licentie, dat draait op allerlei verschillende soorten computers.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KStars jest darmowym, otwartoźródłowym, wieloplatformowym oprogramowaniem astronomicznym stworzonym przez KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KStars é uma aplicação de astronomia com uma licença livre, de código-aberto e multi-plataforma.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KStars é um software de Astronomia do KDE licenciado gratuitamente, de código aberto e multiplataforma.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KStars je slobodný, open source, cross platformový astronomický softvér od KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">KStars je prosta, odprtokodna astronomska programska oprema, ki teče na več okoljih in izdelana pri KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kstars är en astronomiprogramvara med öppen källkod och fri licens för flera plattformar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar; KDE tarafından ücretsiz olarak lisanslanan, açık kaynaklı, çapraz platform bir Astronomi yazılımıdır.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KStars — вільне астрономічне програмне забезпечення з відкритим кодом, яке може працювати на багатьох програмних платформах від KDE.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKStars is freely licensed, open source, cross-platform Astronomy Software by KDE.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 是 KDE 开发的一款自由开源且跨平台的天文软件。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">KStars 是由 KDE 提供的自由授權、開放原始碼、跨平臺的天文學軟體。</p>
    <p>It provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">توفّر البرمجيّة محاكاةً رسوميّة دقيقة لسماء الليل، من أيّ نقطة على سطح الأرض وفي أيّ وقت. يعرض «نجوم‌ك» حوالي ١٠٠ مليون نجم، و١٣٬٠٠٠ جرم سماويّ عميق، والكواكب الثّمانية، والشّمس والقمر وآلاف المذنّبات والكويكبات، والمستعرات العظمى والأقمار الصّناعيّة.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Proporciona una simulació gràfica precisa del cel nocturn, des de qualsevol emplaçament a la Terra, en qualsevol data i hora. La visualització inclou fins a 100 milions d'estrelles, 13.000 objectes del cel profund, tots els 8 planetes, el Sol i la Lluna, milers de cometes, asteroides, supernoves i satèl·lits.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Proporciona una simulació gràfica precisa del cel nocturn, des de qualsevol emplaçament a la Terra, en qualsevol data i hora. La visualització inclou fins a 100 milions d'estreles, 13.000 objectes del cel profund, tots els 8 planetes, el Sol i la Lluna, milers de cometes, asteroides, supernoves i satèl·lits.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">KStars simuliert präzise den Blick in den nächtlichen Himmel von jedem Punkt der Erde aus, zu jedem beliebigen Datum und Uhrzeit. Derzeit gibt es im Planetarium bis zu 100 Millionen Sterne, 13000 Deep-Sky-Objekte, alle acht Planeten, die Sonne und den Mond, sowie tausende Kometen, Asteroiden, Supernovae und Satelliten.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">It provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Ĝi provizas precizan grafikan simuladon de la nokta ĉielo, de iu ajn loko sur la Tero, en ajna dato kaj horo. La ekrano inkluzivas ĝis 100 milionojn da steloj, 13,000 profundaĉielaj objektoj, ĉiuj 8 planedoj, la Suno kaj Luno, kaj miloj da kometoj, asteroidoj, supernovaoj kaj satelitoj.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Proporciona una precisa simulación gráfica del cielo nocturno vista desde cualquier punto de la Tierra y para cualquier fecha y hora. La pantalla muestra unos 100 millones de estrellas, 13.000 objetos del espacio profundo, los 8 planetas, el Sol y la Luna, así como miles de cometas, asteroides, supernovas y satélites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">See võimaldab öise taevapildi täpset graafilist kujutamist mis tahes maakera punktis mis tahes ajal. Näitamisvalikute hulka kuuluvad ligemale 100 miljonit tähte, 13 000 Päikesesüsteemi välist objekti, kõik 8 planeeti, Päike ja Kuu ning tuhanded komeedid, asteroidid, supernoovad ja satelliidid.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Gaueko zeruaren simulazio grafiko zehatza ematen du, lurreko edozein kokalekutik, edozein data eta ordutan. Bistaratzeak 100 milioi izar ditu, 13.000 zeru-sakoneko objektu, 8 planetak, eguzkia eta ilargia, eta milaka kometa, asteroide, supernoba, eta satelite.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Il fournit une simulation graphique précise du ciel nocturne, de n'importe quel endroit sur Terre, à toute date et toute heure. L'affichage comporte plus de 100 millions d'étoiles, 13 000 objets du ciel lointain, toutes les huit planètes, le Soleil et la Lune, des milliers de comètes, d'astéroïdes, supernova et satellites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Fornece un simulador gráfico preciso do ceo nocturno desde calquera lugar do planeta en calquera momento. A visualización inclúe ata 100 millóns de estrelas, 13.000 obxectos do espazo profundo, os 8 planetas, o sol e a lúa, e milleiros de cometas, asteroides, supernovas e satélites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Ini memberikan simulasi grafis yang akurat dari langit malam, dari lokasi mana pun di Bumi, pada tanggal dan waktu apa pun. Termasuk displai hingga 100 juta bintang, 13.000 objek langit, semua 8 planet, Matahari dan Rembulan, dan ribuan komet, asteroid, supernova, dan satelit.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Fornisce una simulazione grafica accurata del cielo notturno, da qualsiasi posizione della Terra, in qualsiasi data e ora. La vista include fino a 100 milioni di stelle, 13.000 oggetti del profondo cielo, tutti e otto i pianeti, il Sole e la Luna oltre a migliaia di comete, asteroidi, supernove e satelliti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Het geeft een nauwkeurige grafische simulatie van de nachtelijke hemel, vanaf elke locatie op aarde, voor elke datum en op elk tijdstip. Er kunnen tot aan 100 miljoen sterren worden afgebeeld, 13000 zogenaamde deepsky-objecten, alle 8 planeten, de zon en de maan, en duizenden kometen, planetoïden, supernova's, en satellieten.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Dostarcza dokładnej graficznej symulacji nieba nocnego z dowolnego miejsca na Ziemi, w dowolnym dniu i o dowolnym czasie. Można wyświetlić do 100 milionów gwiazd, 13000 obiektów z głębokiego nieba, wszystkie 8 planet, Słońce i Księżyc i tysiące komet, asteroidów, supernowych i satelitów. </p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Oferece uma simulação gráfica precisa do céu nocturno, em qualquer ponto da Terra e em qualquer data e hora. A apresentação inclui até 100 milhões de estrelas, 13 000 objectos distantes, todos os 8 planetas, o Sol e a Lua, assim como milhares de cometas, asteróides, supernovas e satélites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Oferece uma simulação gráfica precisa do céu noturno, em qualquer local da Terra à qualquer data e hora. A apresentação inclui até 100 milhões de estrelas, 13.000 objetos distantes, todos os 8 planetas, o Sol e a Lua, assim como milhares de cometas, asteroides, supernovas e satélites.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Poskytuje presnú grafickú simuláciu nočnej oblohy z ľubovoľného miesta na Zemi v ľubovoľný dátum a čas. Zobrazenie zahŕňa do 100 miliónov hviezd, 13000 deep sky objektov, všetkých 8 planét, Slnko a Mesiac a tisíce komét, asteroidov, supernov a satelitov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Ponuja natančno grafično simulacijo nočnega neba z vsakega mesta na Zemlji, ob poljubnem času poljubnega dneva. Prikaz vključuje več kot 100 milijonov zvezd, 13.000 objektov globokega neba, vseh 8 planetov, Sonce in Luno, ter na tisoče kometov, asteroidov, supernov in satelitov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Den erbjuder en noggrann grafisk simulering av natthimlen från vilken plats som helst på jorden, vid vilket datum och vilken tid som helst. Visningen omfattar upp till 100 miljoner stjärnor, 13 000 avlägsna himmelsobjekt, alla 8 planeterna, solen, månen, samt tusentals kometer, asteroider, supernovor och satelliter.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Dünyanın herhangi bir yerinden, herhangi bir tarih ve saatte, gece göğün doğru bir grafik benzetimini sağlar. Ekranda 100 milyona kadar yıldız, 13.000 derin gök nesnesi, 8 gezegenin tümü, Güneş, Ay ve binlerce kuyruklu yıldız, asteroit, süpernova ve uydu bulunur.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Програма точно відтворює вигляд нічного неба з будь-якого місця на Землі у будь-який день та час. Програмі відомі розташування понад 100 мільйонів зірок, 13.000 віддалених об’єктів, 8 планет, Сонця і Місяця, а також тисяч комет, астероїдів, наднових та супутників.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxIt provides an accurate graphical simulation of the night sky, from any location on Earth, at any date and time. The display includes up to 100 million stars, 13,000 deep-sky objects,all 8 planets, the Sun and Moon, and thousands of comets, asteroids, supernovae, and satellites.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 可以精确模拟地球上任意地点、时间的夜空图像。它的视图能够显示多达 1 亿颗恒星、1 万 3000 个深空天体、8 大行星、太阳和月球，以及数千个彗星、小行星、超新星和卫星。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">它提供了準確的夜空圖形化模擬，從地球上的任何地方，在任何日期與時間。顯示了包含一億個星體、一萬三千個深空物體、以及八個系內行星、還有太陽與月亮，以及數千個慧星、小行星、超新星與衛星。</p>
    <p>For students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">إن كنت طالبًا أو أستاذًا، فستجد أنّ البرمجيّة تدعم ضبط سرعة المحاكاة الذي يتيح عرض الظّواهر التي تحدث على فترات زمنيّة طويلة، وتدعم الكثير من الحسابات الفلكيّة المعروفة، وتوفّر حاسبة فلكيّة لتوقّع الاقترانات.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Per a estudiants i professors, permet velocitats de simulació ajustables per tal de veure fenòmens que transcorren en escales de temps llargues, la calculadora astronòmica del KStars per a predir conjuncions i molts càlculs astronòmics habituals.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Per a estudiants i professors, permet velocitats de simulació ajustables per tal de veure fenòmens que transcorren en escales de temps llargues, la calculadora astronòmica de KStars per a predir conjuncions i molts càlculs astronòmics habituals.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Für Schüler und Lehrer unterstützt es einstellbare Simulationsgeschwindigkeiten, um Phänomene zu betrachten, die auf langen Zeitskalen ablaufen, den KStars-Astrorechner zur Vorhersage von Konjunktionen und viele allgemeine astronomische Berechnungen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">For students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Por studentoj kaj instruistoj, ĝi subtenas alĝustigeblajn simulajn rapidojn por vidi fenomenojn kiuj okazas laŭ longaj temposkaloj, la KStars Astrokalkulilo por antaŭdiri konjunkciojn, kaj multajn komunajn astronomiajn kalkulojn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Para estudiantes y profesores, permite ajustar la velocidad de simulación para poder ver fenómenos que ocurren a lo largo de mucho tiempo; la calculadora astronómica de KStars permite predecir conjunciones y realizar cálculos astronómicos comunes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Õpilastele ja õpetajatele on pakkuda muudetava kiirusega matkimised, mis lubavad uurida ka nähtusi, mis toimuvad väga pika aja vältel. KStarsi astrokalkulaator suudab ette ennustada taevakehade ühendusi ja teha veel paljusid astronoomilisi arvutusi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Ikasle eta irakasleentzat, simulazio abiadura erregulagarriak onartzen ditu denbora-eskala luzeetan gertatzen diren fenomenoak ikusi ahal izateko, KStars Astrokalkulagailua konjuntzioak kalkulatzeko, eta kalkulu astronomiko arrunt ugari.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Pour les élèves et les enseignants, il prend en charge des vitesses de simulation ajustables, afin d'afficher des phénomènes arrivant sur de longues périodes de temps. Le module « Astrocalculator » de KStars effectue les prédictions de conjonctions et de nombreux calculs classiques d'astronomie.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Para estudantes e profesores, permite axustar a velocidade da simulación para ver os fenómenos que se producen ao longo de moito tempo, a calculadora de astros de KStars para predicir aliñamentos, e moitos cálculos astronómicos comúns.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Bagi siswa dan guru, ini mendukung kecepatan simulasi yang disesuaikan untuk melihat fenomena yang terjadi dalam jangka waktu yang lama, KStars Astrocalculator untuk memprediksi konjungsi, dan banyak perhitungan astronomi umum.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Per studenti e insegnanti supporta velocità di simulazione regolabili, in modo da poter vedere fenomeni che accadono in tempi molto lunghi, mentre l'astrocalcolatrice di KStars predice le congiunzioni ed esegue molti calcoli astronomici comuni.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Voor leerlingen en docenten zijn aan te passen simulatiesnelheden mogelijk, om hemelverschijnselen zichtbaar te maken die in werkelijkheid heel veel tijd in beslag nemen. De Astrorekenmachine van KStars kan verduisteringen van te voren berekenen, en veel andere gewone sterrenkundige berekeningen uitvoeren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Dla uczniów i nauczycieli, przewidziano zmienne szybkości symulacji celem obserwacji zjawisk zachodzących w dłuższych okresach czasowych, kalkulator astronomiczny do przewidywania koniunkcji oraz wiele innych powszechnych obliczeń astronomicznych.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Para os alunos e professores, suporta velocidades de simulação ajustáveis para poder ver os fenómenos que ocorrem ao longo de largos períodos de tempo, podendo também usar a Calculadora Astronómica para prever as conjunções e muitos outros cálculos astronómicos comuns.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Para alunos e professores, tem suporte a velocidades de simulação ajustáveis para permitir a visualização dos fenômenos que ocorrem em longos períodos de tempo, a Calculadora Astronômica do KStars para prever as conjunções e muitos outros cálculos astronômicos comuns.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Pre študentov a učiteľov, podporuje upraviteľné simulované rýchlosti na zobrazenie fenomén, ktoré nastávajú počas dlhých období, KStars astrokalkulačka na predpovedanie konjunkcií a mnoho bežných astronomických výpočtov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Za študente in učitelje so na voljo prilagodljive hitrosti simulacije za ogled fenomenov, ki se zgodijo v daljših časovnih obdobjih, ter zvezdno računalo KStars za napovedovanje konjunkcij ter številne pogoste astronomske izračune.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">För elever och lärare stöder den justerbar simuleringshastighet för att visa fenomen som inträffar under långa tidsperioder. Kstars astronomiräknare predikterar konjunktioner, och utför många vanliga astronomiska beräkningar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Öğrenciler ve öğretmenler için, uzun zaman ölçeklerinde meydana gelen fenomenleri görüntülemek için ayarlanabilir benzetim hızlarını, kavuşumları tahmin etmek için K Yıldızlar Astro Hesaplayıcı'yı ve birçok yaygın astronomik hesaplamayı destekler.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Для учнів і вчителів, у програмі передбачено підтримку налаштовуваної швидкості імітації з метою перегляду явищ, які тривають дуже довго, астрономічний калькулятор KStars для розрахунку сполучень та багатьох інших астрономічних обчислень.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFor students and teachers, it supports adjustable simulation speeds in order to view phenomena that happen over long timescales, the KStars Astrocalculator to predict conjunctions, and many common astronomical calculations.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">对于学生和教师而言，KStars 支持对模拟速度进行调整，方便观看时间跨度极大的天文现象。KStars 的天体计算器可以用来预测合的发生时间和进行各种常见的天文学计算。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">對於學生與教師來說，它支援了可調整的模擬速度以檢視在極長的時間尺度下發生的現象，KStars Astrocalculator 可用來預測天體會合，也可以用來計算許多常見的天文學數據。</p>
    <p>For the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">توفّر البرمجيّة لهواة الفلك مخطِّطًا للرّؤية، وأداة لتقويم الطّقس، ومحرّرًا لمجال الرّؤية لحساب مجال رؤية العتاد وعرضها. اطّلع على أجرام شيّقة في أداة ”السّماء هذه الليلة“، وارسم رسومًا بيانيّة لخطّ ارتفاع أيّ جرم مقابل وقته، واطبع رسومًا بيانيّة للسّماء بجودة عالية، واقرأ الكثير من المعلومات والموارد لتساعدك في اكتشاف العالم!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Per a l'astrònom aficionat, proporciona un planificador de l'observació, una eina de calendari del cel i un editor del CDV per a calcular el camp de visió de l'equip i mostrar-lo. Descobreix objectes interessants amb l'eina «Què passa aquesta nit», dibuixa gràfics d'altitud en funció del temps per a qualsevol objecte, imprimeix diagrames del cel en alta qualitat i obté accés a molta informació i recursos per a ajudar-vos a explorar l'univers!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Per a l'astrònom aficionat, proporciona un planificador de l'observació, una eina de calendari del cel i un editor de CDV per a calcular el camp de visió de l'equip i mostrar-lo. Descobrix objectes interessants amb l'eina «Què passa esta nit», dibuixa gràfics d'altitud en funció del temps per a qualsevol objecte, imprimix diagrames del cel en alta qualitat i obté accés a molta informació i recursos per a ajudar-vos a explorar l'univers!</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Für den Amateur-Astronomen bietet es einen Beobachtungsplaner, einen Himmelskalender und einen STF-Editor, um Sichtfelder von Geräten zu berechnen und anzuzeigen. Finden Sie interessante Objekte mit „Was ist los heute Nacht“, zeichnen Sie Höhen-Zeit-Diagramme für jedes Objekt, drucken Sie hochwertige Himmelskarten und erhalten Sie Zugang zu vielen Informationen und Ressourcen, die Ihnen bei der Erkundung des Universums helfen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">For the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Por la amatora astronomo, ĝi disponigas observadplaniston, ĉielkalendaran ilon, kaj FOV-redaktilon por kalkuli vidkampon de ekipaĵo kaj montri ilin. Eltrovu interesajn objektojn en la ilo "Kio okazas Ĉi-vespere", grafiku altecon kontraŭ tempo-grafeojn por iu ajn objekto, presigu altkvalitajn ĉielajn diagramojn kaj akiru multajn informojn kaj rimedojn por helpi vin esplori la universon!</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Para el astrónomo aficionado, proporciona un planificador de observaciones, una herramienta de calendario celeste y un editor de campo visual para calcular el campo visual de su equipo y poder mostrarlo. Descubra interesantes objetos con la herramienta «¿Qué ocurre esta noche?», muestre gráficos de altitud frente a hora para cualquier objeto, imprima mapas del cielo de gran calidad y obtenga acceso a gran cantidad de información y recursos que le ayudarán a explorar el universo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Amatöörastronoomile on pakkuda vaatluste kavandamine, taevakalendri tööriist ja vaatevälja kalkulaator varustuse vaatevälja väljaarvutamiseks ja selle kuvamiseks. Huvipakkuvaid objekte aitab leida tööriist "Mis on täna vaadata", kõigi objektide puhul saab koostada kõrguse/aja graafiku, taevakaarte on võimalik kõrge kvaliteediga trükkida ning lisaks pakume rohkelt teavet ja ressursse, mis aitavad sul universumit paremini tundma õppida!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Astronomia-zaleentzat, behaketa planifikatzaile bat dakar, zeruko egutegi tresna bat, eta FOV editore bat ekipamenduaren ikus-eremua kalkulatu eta bistaratzeko. Topatu objektu interesgarriak "Zer berri gaur gauean" tresnan, altitudea denborarekiko grafikoak trazatu edozein objekturentzat, inprimatu kalitate handiko zeruko diagramak, eta eskuratu ezazu unibertsoa esploratzen lagunduko dizun informazio eta baliabide ugarietara sarbidea!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Pour l'astronome amateur, il fournit un planificateur d'observation, un outil de calendrier pour le ciel et un éditeur « CdV » (Champ de vision) pour calculer le champs d'observation des équipements et les afficher. Vous pouvez aussi trouver des objets intéressants dans l'outil « Quoi de neuf ce soir », tracer une courbe altitude en fonction du temps pour n'importe quel objet, imprimer des cartes du ciel en haute qualité et avoir accès à beaucoup d'autres informations et ressources pour vous aider à explorer l'univers !</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Para astrónomos afeccionados fornece un planificador de observación, unha ferramenta de calendario celeste, e un editor de campo de visión para calcular o campo de visión de equipamento e mostralo. Descobre obxectos interesantes coa ferramenta «Que pasa esta noite?», xera gráficos de altitude e tempo para calquera obxecto, imprime cartas celestes de gran calidade, e obtén acceso a unha morea de información e recursos para axudarte a explorar o universo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Bagi astronom amatir, ia menyediakan perencana observasi, alat kalender langit, dan editor FOV untuk menghitung bidang pandang peralatan dan menampilkannya. Temukan benda-benda menarik di alat "What's up Tonight", plot ketinggian vs grafik waktu untuk objek apa pun, cetak bagan langit berkualitas tinggi, dan dapatkan akses ke banyak informasi dan sumberdaya untuk membantu Anda menjelajahi alam semesta!</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Fornisce agli astronomi dilettanti un pianificatore di osservazione, uno strumento per il calendario celeste e un editor di CDV per calcolare il campo di vista dell'equipaggiamento e per visualizzarlo. Trova gli oggetti interessanti con lo strumento «Cosa si vede stanotte», traccia l'altezza in funzione del tempo di qualsiasi oggetto, esegue stampe in alta qualità della mappa celeste, e fornisce inoltre l'accesso a molte informazioni e a risorse che ti aiutano ad esplorare l'universo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Voor de amateur astronoom is er een observatieplanner, een hemelkalender, en een GV-bewerker voor het berekenen van het gezichtsveld van apparatuur, en het afbeelden daarvan. Ontdek interessante waarneemobjecten in het hulpmiddel voor Wat er vanavond te zien is, hoogtes te berekenen van enig object, als functie van de tijd, zeer goede hemelkaarten af te drukken, en toegang te verkrijgen tot een enorm scala aan informatie en bronnen waarmee u het heelal kunt onderzoeken!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Dla astronomów-amatorów, przewidziano harmonogram obserwacji, kalendarz nieba i edytor pola widzenia do obliczania i wyświetlania pola widzenia sprzętu. Dowiaduje się o interesujących obiektach z narzędzia "Co dzisiaj na niebie", rysuj wykresy wysokości względem czasu dla dowolnych obiektów, drukuj wykresy nieba w wysokiej jakości i zyskuj dostęp do wielu informacji i zasobów mających na celu pomóc tobie w odkrywaniu wszechświata!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Para o astrónomo amador, oferece um planeamento de observações, uma ferramenta de calendário do céu e um editor de CDV para calcular o campo de visão de um dado equipamento, bem como para o apresentar. Descubra objectos interessantes na ferramenta "O Que se Passa Esta Noite", gráficos da altitude vs. tempo para qualquer objecto, a impressão de gráficos do céu de alta qualidade e o acesso a bastante informação e recursos que o ajudam a explorar o Universo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Para o astrônomo amador, oferece um planejamento de observações, uma ferramenta de calendário do céu e um editor de CDV para calcular e exibir o campo de visão do equipamento. Encontre objetos interessantes na ferramenta "O que acontece esta noite", gráficos da altitude vs. tempo para qualquer objeto, a impressão de gráficos do céu em alta qualidade e o acesso a muitas informações e recursos que o ajudam a explorar o universo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Pre amatérskeho astronóma poskytuje plánovať pozorovaní, nástroj nebeského kalendára a FOV editor na výpočet príslušenstva a ich zobrazenie. Nájdite zaujímavé objekty v nástroji "Čo je vidno dnes", zakreslite si graf výšky podľa času pre ľubovoľný objekt, vytlačte grafy oblohy vo vysokej kvalite a získajte prístup k mnohým informáciám a zdrojom, ktoré vám pomôžu skúmať vesmír!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Amaterskemu astronomu ponuja načrtovalnik opazovanja, nebesni koledarček ter urejevalnik vidnega polja za izračun vidnega polja opreme in njihov prikaz. Z orodjem »Kaj je danes na nebu« se lahko pozanimate o zanimivih objektih, izrišete grafikone višine nasproti času za poljuben objekt, natisnete visokokakovostne nebesne karte ter pridobite dostop do velike količine podatkov in virov, ki vam bodo v pomoč pri raziskovanju vesolja!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">För amatörastronomer tillhandahåller den observationsplanering, ett verktyg med en himmelskalender, och en synfältseditor för att beräkna utrustningens synfält och visa det. Ta reda på intressanta objekt med verktyget "Vad händer inatt", skapa diagram över elevation över tid för vilket objekt som helst, skriv ut himmelskartor med hög kvalitet, och få tillgång till massor med information och resurser för att hjälpa till att utforska universum.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Amatör gökbilimci için, ekipmanın görüş alanını hesaplamak ve görüntülemek için bir gözlem planlayıcı, bir gök takvimi aracı ve bir FOV düzenleyici sağlar. "Bu Gece Neler Var" aracında ilginç nesneleri bulun, herhangi bir nesne için yükseklik-zaman grafikleri çizin, yüksek kaliteli gök haritaları yazdırın ve evreni keşfetmenize yardımcı olacak birçok bilgi ve kaynağa erişin!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Для астрономів-аматорів у програмі передбачено засіб планування спостережень, небесний календар та редактор поля здору для визначення поля зору обладнання та його показу. Ви зможете шукати цікаві об’єкти для спостереження за допомогою засобу «Сьогодні ввечері», переглядати графіки висота-час для усіх об’єктів, друкувати високоякісні карти неба та отримаєте доступ до багатьох інформаційних ресурсів та ресурсів із мультимедійними даними, які допоможуть вам вивчати всесвіт!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFor the amateur astronomer, it provides an observation planner, a sky calendar tool, and an FOV editor to calculate field of view of equipment and display them. Find out interesting objects in the "What's up Tonight" tool, plot altitude vs. time graphs for any object, print high-quality sky charts, and gain access to lots of information and resources to help you explore the universe!xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">对于业余天文爱好者而言，KStars 提供了观测计划、星空日历等工具。它还具备视场编辑器，可用于计算设备的视场并按此显示视图。您还可以使用“今夜天象”工具来发现值得观测的天体，为任意天体按高度角和时间规划图表，打印高品质星图，获取大量有助于探索宇宙星空奥秘的信息和资源等。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">對於業餘天文學家來說，它提供了觀測計劃器、天空日曆工具、FOV 編輯器來計算裝備的視野並顯示它們。在「今晚有什麼」工具中尋找有趣的目標、繪製任何物體的高度與時間關係圖，列印高品質的天空圖，並取得大量資訊與資源來協助您探索宇宙！</p>
    <p>Included with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">تأتي مع «نجوم‌ك» مجموعة «إيكوس» للتّصوير الفلكيّ، وهي حلّ كامل للتّصوير الفلكيّ والذي يتحكّم بكلّ أجهزة INDI بما في ذلك التّلسكوبات بأنواعها، ومجسّات CCD، وكمرات DSLR، والمُركِّزات، والمرشّحات وغيرها الكثير. يدعم «إيكوس» التّعقّب بدقّة عالية وذلك باستخدام الحلّال الفلكيّ (بتوفّر الشّابكة أو بدونها) وإمكانيّات التّركيز الآليّ والتّوجيه الآليّ، ويلتقط أيضًا الصّور (مفردةً وبمجموعات) باستخدام مدير التّسلسل القويّ المضمّن في البرمجيّة.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Inclòs amb el KStars hi ha el paquet astrofotogràfic Ekos, una solució completa d'astrofotografia que pot controlar tots els dispositius INDI, inclosos nombrosos telescopis, CCD, DSLR, enfocadors, filtres i molt més. L'Ekos admet el seguiment d'alta precisió emprant el solucionador d'astrometria en línia i fora de línia, té capacitats d'enfocament automàtic i de guiatge automàtic, i permet capturar una o múltiples imatges emprant el potent gestor de seqüències integrat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Inclòs amb KStars hi ha el paquet astrofotogràfic Ekos, una solució completa d'astrofotografia que pot controlar tots els dispositius INDI, inclosos nombrosos telescopis, CCD, DSLR, enfocadors, filtres i molt més. Ekos admet el seguiment d'alta precisió emprant el solucionador d'astrometria en línia i fora de línia, té capacitats d'enfocament automàtic i de guiatge automàtic, i permet capturar una o múltiples imatges emprant el potent gestor de seqüències integrat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Im Lieferumfang von KStars ist das Astrofotografie-Programm Ekos enthalten, eine komplette Astrofotografie-Lösung, die alle INDI-Geräte steuern kann, darunter zahlreiche Teleskope, CCDs, DSLRs, Fokussierer, Filter und vieles mehr. Ekos unterstützt hochpräzise Nachführung mit Online- und Offline-Astrometrie-Lösung, automatischer Fokussierung und Automatischer Nachführung sowie die Aufnahme von Einzel- oder Mehrfachbildern mit dem leistungsstarken eingebauten Verwaltung von Aufnahmesequenzen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Included with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Inkluzivita kun KStars estas Ekos astrofotografia aro, kompleta astrofotografia solvo kiu povas kontroli ĉiujn INDI-aparatojn inkluzive de multaj teleskopoj, CCD-oj, DSLR-oj, fokusiloj, filtriloj kaj multe pli. Ekos subtenas tre precizan spuradon per interreta kaj eksterrete astrometria solvanto, aŭtomata fokuso kaj aŭtogvidkapabloj, kaj kaptado de unuopaj aŭ pluraj bildoj per la potenca enkonstruita sinsekva administranto.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">KStars incluye la suite de astrofotografía Ekos, una completa solución de fotografía astronómica que puede controlar cualquier dispositivo INDI, como telescopios, cámaras CCD y DSLR, sistemas de enfoque y filtros, entre otros. Ekos permite un seguimiento de alta precisión mediante el uso de sistemas de identificación con y sin conexión, funciones de enfoque y de guiado automáticos, así como la captura de una o múltiples imágenes mediante el uso de potente gestor de secuencias que integra.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">KStarsiga on kaasas astrofotograafiakomplekt Ekos, mis kujutab endast kõikehõlmavat astrofotograafia lahendust, millega saab juhtida INDI-seadmeid, sealhulgas paljusid teleskoope, CCD-sid, digitaalseid peegelkaamerraid (DSLR), fokuseerijaid, filtreid ja paljut muud. Ekos toetab äärmiselt täpset jälgimist nii võrgu- kui ka autonoomsete astromeetriaprogrammidega, automaatset fokuseerimist ja gideerimist ning ühe või paljude piltide tegemist kaasasoleva võimsa sarivõtete halduriga.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">KStars-ekin batera Ekos astro-argazkigintza suitea dator, astro-argazkigintza soluzio oso bat INDI gailu guztiak kontrolatu ditzakeena tartean teleskopio ugari, CCDak, DSLRak, fokatzaileak, iragazkiak, eta askoz gehiago. Ekos-ek zehaztasun handiko jarraipena onartzen du lerroko eta lerroz kanpoko astrometria ebazleak erabiliz, auto-fokua eta auto-gidatze gaitasunak, eta irudi bakar edo anitzak atzematea barnean eraikia duen sekuentzia kudeatzaile ahaltsua erabiliz.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">KStarsin mukana tulee Ekos-tähtivalokuvausohjelmisto, täydellinen tähtivalokuvaustaratkaisu, jolla voi hallita kaikkia INDI-laitteita kuten kaukoputkia, CCD- ja DSLR-kameroita, kohdistimia, suodattimia ja paljon muuta. Ekos tukee tarkkaa jäljitystä verkollisella ja verkottomalla astrometriaratkaisimella automaattikohdistus ja -opastusominaisuuksin sekä niin yksittäisten kuin useampien kuvien ottamista tehokkaalla sisään rakennetulla sekvenssinhallinnalla.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Faisant partie de KStars, la suite d'astrophotographie Ekos est une solution complète d'astrophotographie, contrôlant tous les périphériques INDI, dont de nombreux télescopes, des caméras CCD, des appareils photo numériques, des viseurs, des filtres et bien plus. Ekos prend en charge le suivi en haute précision en utilisant des résolveurs en ligne ou hors ligne, des capacités de mise au point et de guidage automatique et l'acquisition d'images simples ou multiples grâce à un puissant outil de gestionnaire de séquence.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">KStar inclúe a colección de software de astrofotografía Ekos, unha solución completa de astrofotografía que pode controlar todos os dispositivos INDI, incluídos moitos telescopios, CCDs, DSLRs, enfocadores, filtros e moito máis. Ekos permite facer seguimentos moi precisos mediante un resolvedor de astrometría por Internet e sen Internet, goza de capacidade para enforcar e guiar automaticamente, e permite capturar unha ou varias imaxes usando un potente xestor de secuencias que vai incluído.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Yang termasuk dengan KStars adalah Ekos astrophotography suite, solusi astrophotography lengkap yang dapat mengendalikan semua peranti INDI termasuk banyak teleskop, CCD, DSLR, fokus, filter, dan banyak lagi. Ekos mendukung pelacakan yang sangat akurat menggunakan pemecah astrometri online dan offline, kemampuan fokus otomatis dan autoguiding, dan menangkap gambar tunggal atau ganda menggunakan pengelola urutan yang kuat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Inclusa con KStars c'è la suite per l'astrofotografia Ekos, una soluzione completa che può controllare tutti dispositivi INDI, inclusi numerosi telescopi, CCD, DSLR, focheggiatori, filtri e molto altro ancora. Ekos supporta un inseguimento altamente accurato, usando sia dei risolutori astrometrici sul web sia locali, ha capacità di messa a fuoco automatica e di autoguida, oltre a poter catturare immagini singole o multiple grazie al potente gestore di sequenze incorporato.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Tot KStars behoren ook de programma's van Ekos Astrophotography, een complete oplossing voor sterrenfotografie, waarmee alle INDI-apparaten kunnen worden bestuurd, inclusief talloze telescopen, CCD's, DSLR's, focusers, filters, en veel meer. Met Ekos kunt u sterren zeer nauwkeurig volgen met behulp van online en offline astrometrische berekeningen, er zijn mogelijkheden voor autofocus en autovolgen, en voor opnames van enkele of meerdere afbeeldingen, met gebruik van een ingebouwde mogelijkheid tot het beheren van een serie opnames.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Do KStars dołączono pakiet astrofotograficzny Ekos, pełne rozwiązanie astrofotograficzne, które ma możliwość sterowania wszystkimi urządzeniami INDI włączając w to wiele teleskopów, CCD,DSLR, układy ogniskujące, filtry i wiele innych. Ekos obsługuje wysoce dokładne naprowadzanie przy użyciu lokalnych i internetowych programów do rozwiązywania, możliwości samoogniskowania i samonaprowadzania oraz przechwytywanie pojedynczych i wielu obrazów przy użyciu zaawansowanego zarządzania sekwencjami.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Incluído com o KStars vem o pacote de astro-fotografia Ekos, uma solução completa de fotografia na astronomia, que pode controlar todos os dispositivos INDI, incluindo os numerosos telescópios, CCD's, DSLR's, sistemas de focagem, filtros, entre muitas outras coisas. O Ekos suporta o seguimento altamente preciso de objectos, usando o sistema de resolução 'online' e 'offline' Astrometry, as capacidades de focagem e guia automáticos, assim como a captura de imagens individuais ou múltiplas, usando o poderoso gestor de sequências.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Junto com o KStars vem a suíte de astrofotografia Ekos, uma solução completa de astrofotografia que consegue controlar todos os dispositivos INDI, incluindo diversos telescópios, CCDs, DSLRs, focalizadores, filtros, e muito mais. O Ekos tem suporte ao rastreamento altamente preciso usando o sistema de resolução online e offline 'astrometry', capacidade de focagem e guia automáticas, assim como a captura de imagens individuais ou múltiplas, usando o poderoso gerenciador de sequências integrado.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KStars obsahuje astrofotografický balík Ekos, kompletné riešenie, ktoré vie ovládať všetky INDI zariadenia vrátane mnohých ďalekohľadov, CCD, DSLR, približovače, filtre a omnoho viac. Ekos podporuje vysoko presné sledovanie pomocou online a offline astrometrického riešiteľa, automatické zaostrovanie a navádzanie a snímanie jednej alebo viac snímok pomocou silného správcu sekvencií.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">V KStars je vključen tudi Etos, astronomski fotografski paket, popolna rešitev za astrofotografijo, s katero lahko nadzirate vse naprave INDI, vključno s številnimi daljnogledi, CCD-ji, DSLR-ji, ostrilci, filtri, itd. Ekos podpira zelo natančno sledenje z uporabo spletnega in nepovezanega reševalnika astrometry.net, zmogljivosti samodejnega ostrenja in sledenja ter zajem posamičnih ali zaporednih slik z zmogljivim vgrajenim upravljalnikom zaporedij.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Ekos astronomifotograferingssvit ingår i Kstars: en fullständig lösning för astronomisk fotografering som kan styra alla INDI-enheter, inklusive en mängd teleskop, CCD:er, digitala spegelreflexkameror, fokuseringsenheter, filter, med mera. Ekos stöder mycket noggrann följning med ett nätbaserat och lokalt astrometrilösningsverktyg, har möjlighet till automatisk fokusering och guidning, samt tagning av enstaka eller flera bilder med den kraftfulla inbyggda sekvenshanteraren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar'a, çok sayıda teleskop, CCD, DSLR, odaklayıcı, süzgeç ve çok daha fazlasını içeren tüm INDI aygıtlarını denetleyebilen eksiksiz bir astrofotoğrafçılık çözümü olan Ekos astrofotoğrafçılık paketi dahildir. Ekos, çevrimiçi ve çevrimdışı astrometri çözücü, otomatik odaklama ve otomatik yönlendirme özelliklerini kullanarak son derece hassas izlemeyi ve güçlü yerleşik sıralama yöneticisini kullanarak tekli veya çoklu görsellerin yakalanmasını destekler.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">До складу пакунків з KStars включено астрометричний розв’язувач Ekos — повноцінне астрографічне рішення, яке може керувати усіма пристроями INDI, зокрема багатьма телескопами, ПЗЗ, цифровими дзеркальними фотокамерами, засобам фокусування, фільтрами та іншими інструментами. У Ekos передбачено підтримку високоточного стеження за допомогою засобів інтерактивної та авторомної астрометрії, автофокусування та автонаведення, можливості захоплення одного або декількох зображень на основі потужного вбудованого засобу керування зйомкою.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxIncluded with KStars is Ekos astrophotography suite, a complete astrophotography solution that can control all INDI devices including numerous telescopes, CCDs, DSLRs, focusers, filters, and a lot more. Ekos supports highly accurate tracking using online and offline astrometry solver, autofocus and autoguiding capabilities, and capture of single or multiple images using the powerful built in sequence manager.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 还内建了 Ekos 天文摄影套件。Ekos 是一套完整的天体摄影解决方案，能够控制所有 INDI 设备，包括各种望远镜、CCD、DSLR、电调、滤镜和更多其他设备。Ekos 支持使用在线和离线天体测量解析器进行高精确度跟踪、自动聚焦和自动导星功能，以及使用内建的序列管理器拍摄单个或多个图像。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">包含在 KStars 中的是 Ekos 天文攝影套裝軟體，這是一套可以控制所有 INDI 裝置的完整解決方案，其中包含了眾多望遠鏡、CCS、DSLR、聚焦器、濾光片與許多其他東西。Ekos 使用線上與離線的天體測量計算程式、自動對焦與自動導航功能進行高精度追蹤，並使用功能強大的序列管理程式來照出一張或多張照片。</p>
    <p>Astronomical Catalogs:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">الفهارس الفلكيّة:</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Astronomski katalozi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs astronòmics:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs astronòmics:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Astronomické katalogy:</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Astronomische Kataloge:</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Astronomical Catalogues:</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Astronomiaj Katalogoj:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Catálogos astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Tähekataloogid:</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Katalogo astronomikoak:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Tähtitieteelliset luettelot:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Catalogues astronomiques :</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Catálogos astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Katalog Astronomi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Cataloghi astronomici:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">천문 카탈로그:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Astronoomsch Katalogen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Astronomische catalogi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Astronomikatalogar:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਖਾਗੋਲਸ਼ਾਲਾ ਸੂਚੀਆਂ:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Katalogi astronomiczne:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Catálogos Astronómicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos astronômicos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Астрономические каталоги:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Astronomické katalógy:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Astronomski katalogi:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Astronomiska kataloger:</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Astronomik Kataloglar:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Каталоги астрономічних даних:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxAstronomical Catalogs:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">天文数据库：</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">天文類別：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Default catalog consisting of stars to magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ar">الفهرس المبدئيّ والذي يحتوي النّجوم حتّى القدْر ٨</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Uobičajeni Katalog se sastoji od zvijezda do magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàleg predeterminat consistent en estrelles fins a magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàleg predeterminat consistent en estreles fins a magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Standardkatalog mit Sternen bis zur Magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Default catalogue consisting of stars to magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Defaŭlta katalogo konsistanta el steloj ĝis magnitudo 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">El catálogo por omisión contiene estrellas hasta la magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Vaikimisi kataloog sisaldab tähti kuni tähesuuruseni 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="eu">Katalogo lehenetsia, 8 magnitude arteko izarrak dituena</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Oletusluettelo sisältää tähdet suuruusluokkaan 8 saakka</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Le catalogue par défaut contient des étoiles jusqu'à la magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogo predeterminado composto de estrelas de magnitudes 8 e inferiores.</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Katalog baku yang terdiri dari bintang dengan magnitudo 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Il catalogo predefinito, formato da stelle di magnitudo 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Standardkataloog mit Steerns bet Magnituud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Standaard catalogus met sterren tot magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Domyślny katalog zawierający gwiazdy wielkości 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogo predefinido que consiste nas estrelas de magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogo padrão que consiste nas estrelas de magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Основной каталог содержит звёзды до 8 величины</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Predvolený katalóg obsahujúci hviezdy do magnitúdy 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Privzeti katalog, ki vsebuje zvezde do magnitude 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Standardkatalog som består av stjärnor till magnitud 8</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">8 kadire kadar yıldızlardan oluşan öntanımlı katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">типовий каталог з зірками до зоряної величини 8;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDefault catalog consisting of stars to magnitude 8xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">默认星表涵盖了 8 等星及以上恒星</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">包含星等 8 的預設類別</li>
      <li>Extra catalogs consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ar">فهارس أخرى فيها ما يقارب ١٠٠ مليون نجم حتّى القدْر ١٦</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Prošireni katalozi koji se sastoji od 100 milijuna zvijezda u veličini 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs addicionals consistents en 100 milions d'estrelles fins a magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs addicionals consistents en 100 milions d'estreles fins a magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Zusätzliche Kataloge mit 100 Millionen Sternen bis zur Magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Extra catalogues consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Ekstraj katalogoj konsistantaj el 100 milionoj da steloj ĝis magnitudo 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Los catálogos adicionales contienen 100 millones de estrellas hasta la magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Lisakataloogid sisaldavad 100 miljonit tähte kuni tähesuuruseni 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="eu">Katalogo gehigarriak, 16 magnitude arteko 100 milioi izar dituztenak</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Lisäluettelo sisältää 100 miljoonaa tähteä suuruusluokkaan 16 saakka</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">D'autres catalogues contiennent 100 millions d'étoiles jusqu'à la magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogos adicionais con 100 millóns de estrelas de magnitudes ata a 16.</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Katalog ekstra yang terdiri dari 100 juta bintang dengan magnitudo 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Dei cataloghi aggiuntivi formati da 100 milioni di stelle fino alla magnitudo 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Bito-Katalogen mit 100 Millionen Steerns bet Magnituud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Extra catalogi met 100 miljoen sterren tot magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Ekstra katalogi zawierające 100 milionów gwiazd wielkości 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogos extra que consistem em 100 milhões de estrelas até à magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos adicionais que consistem em 100 milhões de estrelas de magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Дополнительные каталоги содержат 100 миллионов звёзд до 16 величины</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Dodatočné katalógy obsahujúce 100 miliónov hviezd do magnitúdy 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Dodatni katalogi, ki vsebujejo 100 milijonov zvezd do magnitude 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Extra kataloger bestående av 100 millioner stjärnor till magnitud 16</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">16 kadire kadar 100 milyon yıldızdan oluşan ek kataloglar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">додаткові каталоги з 100 мільйонами зірок до зоряної величини 16;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxExtra catalogs consisting of 100 million stars to magnitude 16xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">附加星表涵盖了从最暗到 16 等星的一亿多颗恒星</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">包含到星等 16 的一億個星體的額外類別</li>
      <li>Downloadable catalogs including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="ar">فهارس يمكن تنزيلها وتشمل صور ميسييه، و”أَبِلّ“ للسُّدم الكوكبيّة، وفهرس ”شَارپْلِس“، وفهرس ”لُوِند“ للسُّدم المعتمة</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Catàlegs descarregables que inclouen imatges de Messier, la nebulosa planetària Abell, el catàleg Sharpless, el catàleg Lynds de nebuloses fosques</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Catàlegs descarregables que inclouen imatges de Messier, la nebulosa planetària Abell, el catàleg Sharpless, el catàleg Lynds de nebuloses fosques</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Herunterladbare Kataloge einschließlich Messier-Bilder, Abell-Katalog, Sharpless-Katalog und Lynds Dunkelnebel-Katalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Downloadable catalogues including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalogue, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalogue</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Elŝuteblaj katalogoj inkluzive de Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Los catálogos que puede descargar contienen imágenes de objetos Messier, Nebulosas planetarias Abell, el Catálogo Sharpless y el catálogo de nebulosas oscuras Lynds</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Allalaaditavad kataloogid, sealhulgas Messieri pildid, Abelli planetaarudukogud, Sharplessi kataloog, Lyndsi tumedate udukogude kataloog</li>
      <li xml:lang="eu">Jaitsi daitezkeen katalogoak, haien artean Messier Irudiak, Abell Planeten Nebulosa, Sharpless Katalogoa, Lynds Nebulosa Iluna katalogoa</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Ladattavia luetteloita kuten Messier-kuvat, planetaaristen sumujen Abell-luettelo, Sharpless-luettelo ja pimeiden sumujen Lynds-luettelo</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Les catalogues pouvant être téléchargés contiennent des images du catalogue de Messier, les nébuleuses planétaires de du catalogues d'Abell, le catalogue Sharpless et le catalogue de nébuleuses Lynds Dark.</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Catálogos dispoñíbeis para descarga entre os que hai imaxes de Messier, as nebulosas planetarias Abell, o catálogo Sharpless ou o catálogo de nebulosa escura de Lynds.</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Katalog yang bisa diunduh termasuk Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Altri cataloghi scaricabili, che includono le immagini Messier, le nebulose planetarie di Abell, il catalogo Sharpless e il catalogo delle nebulose oscure di Lynds</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Catalogi die kunnen worden gedownload, met inbegrip van Messier objecten, Abell planetaire nevels, Sharpless Catalogus, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog (catalogus donkere nevels)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Katalogi do pobrania zawierające obrazy Messier, Mgławicę planetarną Abell, Katalog Sharpless, Katalog Lynds Dark Nebula</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Catálogos disponíveis para transferência, incluindo as imagens Messier, as Nebulosas Planetárias Abell, o Catálogo Sharpless e o Catálogo de Nebulosas Escuras Lynds</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Catálogos disponíveis para transferência, incluindo as imagens Messier, Nebulosas Planetárias Abell, Catálogo Sharpless e o Catálogo de Nebulosas Escuras Lynds</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Stiahnuteľné katalógy obsahujúce Messierove obrázky, Abellove planetárne hmloviny, Sharpless Catalog, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Katalogi, ki jih je mogoče prejeti in vsebujejo Messierjeve slike, Abellove planetarne meglice, Sharplessov katalog in Lyndsov katalog temnih meglic</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Nerladdningsbara kataloger som omfattar Messier-bilder, Abell planetära nebulosor, Sharpless-katalog, Lynds katalog över mörka nebulosor</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Messier Görselleri, Abell Gezegenimsi Bulutsuları, Sharpless Kataloğu ve Lynds Dark Bulutsu Kataloğu da içerilmek üzere indirilebilir kataloglar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">придатні до отримання каталоги з зображеннями об’єктів каталогу Месьє, каталогу планетарних туманностей Абеля та каталогу Шарплеса, каталогу темних туманностей Ліндса;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDownloadable catalogs including Messier Images, Abell Planetary Nebulae, Sharpless Catalog, Lynds Dark Nebula Catalogxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">可下载星表包括：梅西叶星云星团表、Abell 行星星云、沙普利斯亮星云表、林茨暗星云表</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">可下載的分類，包括 Messier images、Abell Planetary Nebulae、Sharpless Catalog、Lynds Dark Nebula Catalog 等</li>
      <li>Corrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refraction</li>
      <li xml:lang="ar">تصحيح الدّقّة والانحراف والانكسار الجوّيّ</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Korekcije za precesiju, njihanje i atmosferske refrakcije</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Correccions per a la precessió, nutació i refracció atmosfèrica</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Correccions per a la precessió, nutació i refracció atmosfèrica</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Korrekturen für Präzession, Nutation und atmosphärische Brechung</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Corrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refraction</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Korektoj por precesio, nutado kaj atmosfera refrakto</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Correcciones de precesión, nutación y refracción atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Pretsessiooni, nutatsiooni ja atmosfääri refraktsiooni korrigeerimine</li>
      <li xml:lang="eu">Zuzenketak prezesioentzat, nutazioarentzat eta errefrakzio atmosferikoarentzat</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Korjaukset presessiolle, nutaatiolle ja ilmakehätaittumiselle</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Corrections pour la précession, la nutation et les réfractions atmosphériques.</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Correccións de precesión, nutación e refracción atmosférica.</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Koreksi untuk presesi, lenggut dan refraksi atmosfer</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Correzioni per precessione, nutazione e rifrazione atmosferica</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Richten för Küselbewegen, Eerass-Swunken un atmosfeersch Lichtbreken</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Correcties voor precessie, nutatie en atmosferische straalbreking</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Poprawki do precesji, nutacji i załamania atmosferycznego</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Correcções da precessão, nutação e refracção atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correções da precessão, nutação e refração atmosférica</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Поправки на прецессию, нутацию и атмосферную рефракцию</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Korekcie pre precesiu, nutáciu a atmosférickú refrakciu</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Popravki precesije, nutacije in loma v ozračju</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Korrektion för precession, nutation och atmosfärisk refraktion</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Ekinoks devinimi, üğrem ve atmosferik kırılmalar için düzeltmeler</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">виправлення прецесії, нутації та атмосферної рефракції;</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCorrections for precession, nutation and atmospheric refractionxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">可针对岁差、章动和大气折射进行校正</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">歲差、地軸震動與大氣磨擦修正</li>
      <li>Tools for retrieval of data from online databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="ar">أدوات لجلب البيانات من قواعد البيانات الشّبكيّة</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Alati za preuzimanje podataka iz mrežnih baza podataka</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Eines per a recuperar dades des d'una base de dades en línia</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Eines per a recuperar dades des d'una base de dades en línia</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Nástroje pro získávání dat z databází online</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Werkzeuge zum Herunterladen von Daten aus Online-Datenbanken</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Tools for retrieval of data from online databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Iloj por retrovo de datumoj de interretaj datumbazoj</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Herramientas de obtención de datos de bases de datos en línea</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Võimalus hankida andmeid võrguandmebaasidest</li>
      <li xml:lang="eu">Lerroko datu-baseetatik datuak-berreskuratzerako tresnak</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Työkalut aineiston hakemiseen verkossa olevista tietokannoista</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Outils pour télécharger des données à partir de bases de données en ligne</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Ferramentas para obter datos de bases de datos en Internet.</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Peralatan untuk penerimaan data dari database online</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Strumenti per il recupero di dati dalle base di dati in linea</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Warktüüch för't Halen vun Daten ut Tokoppel-Datenbanken</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddelen voor het verkrijgen van gegevens uit gegevensbanken vanaf het internet</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Narzędzia do pobierania danych z internetowych baz danych</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ferramentas de obtenção de dados a partir de bases de dados 'online'</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramentas para obtenção de dados dos bancos de dados online</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">Инструменты для получения данных из онлайновых баз данных</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Nástroje na získanie všetkých údajov zo všetkých online databáz</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Orodja za pridobivanje podatkov iz spletnih podatkovnih zbirk</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Verktyg för hämtning av data från databaser på nätet</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Çevrimiçi veritabanlarından veri alımı için araçlar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">інструменти для отримання даних з баз даних у інтернеті.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxTools for retrieval of data from online databasesxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">用于检索在线数据库数据的工具</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">顯示線上資料庫的工具</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://kstars.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kstars</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.kde.org/?application=kstars</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>KStars main window</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">النافذة الرئسية لنجومك</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Finestra principal del KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Finestra principal de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Hlavní okno KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Hauptfenster von KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">KStars main window</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Ĉeffenestro de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Ventana principal de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">KStarsi peaaken</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Kstars leiho nagusia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">KStarsin pääikkuna</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Fenêtre principale de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Xanela principal de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Jendela utama KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Finestra principale di KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">KStars -ის მთავარი ფანჯარა</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Het hoofdvenster van KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Hovudvindauget i KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pa">ਕੇ-ਤਾਰੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਵਿੰਡੋ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Główne okno KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Janela principal do KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Janela principal do KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">KStars hlavné okno</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Glavno okno KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Huvudfönstret i Kstars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar'ın ana penceresi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Головне вікно KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxKStars main windowxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 主窗口</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">KStars 主視窗</caption>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kstars/kstars_main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>"What's interesting" tool in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">أداة "ما المثير؟" في نجومك</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Eina «Què hi ha d'interessant» al KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Eina «Què hi ha d'interessant» en KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Nástroj "Co je zajímavé! v KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">„Was ist interessant“ in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">"What's interesting" tool in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">"Kio estas interesa" ilo en KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Herramienta «Qué es interesante» de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">KStarsi tööriist "Mida huvitavat on vaadata"</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">"Zer berri gaur gauean" tresna KStars-en</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">”Mikä on kiinnostavaa” -työkalu KStarsissa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Outil « Quoi d'intéressant » de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Ferramenta de «Que hai de interesante» de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Alat "What's interesting" di KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Strumento "Cosa c'è di interessante" in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Het hulpmiddel voor "Wat is interessant" in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Narzędzie "Co jest interesującego" w KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Ferramenta "O que há de interessante" no KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramenta "O que há de interessante..." no KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Orodje "Kaj je zanimivega" v programu KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Verktyget "Vad är intressant" i Kstars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar'daki "İlginç Neler Var" aracı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Інструмент «Цікаві об'єкти» у KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xx"What's interesting" tool in KStarsxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 的“有趣天体”工具</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">「有哪些有趣的東西」工具在 KStars 中</caption>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kstars/kstars_interesting.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Ekos tool in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">أداة ايكوس في نجومك</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Eina Ekos al KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Eina Ekos en KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Nástroj Ekos v KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Ekos in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Ekos tool in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Ekos-ilo en KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Herramienta Ekos en KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">KStarsi Ekosi tööriist</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Ekos tresnak KStars-en</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Ekos-työkalu KStarsissa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Outil Ekos de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Ferramenta de Ekos de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Alat Ekos di KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Strumento Ekos in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Het hulpmiddel Ekos in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Narzędzie Ekos w KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Ferramenta do Ekos no KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramenta Ekos no KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Nástroj Ekos v KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Orodje Ekos v KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Ekos-verktyget i Kstars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar'daki Ekos aracı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Інструмент Ekos у KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxEkos tool in KStarsxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 的 Ekos 工具</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">Ekos 工具在 Kstars 中</caption>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kstars/kstars_ekos.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Observation Planner of KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">مخطط رصد لنجومك</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Planificador de l'observació del KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Planificador de l'observació de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Plánovač pozorování KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Beobachtungsliste von KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Observation Planner of KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Observejo de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Planificador de observación de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">KStarsi vaatluste plaanija</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">KStars-en behaketa planifikatzailea</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Havaintosuunnittelutyökalu KStarsissa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Planificateur d'observation de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Planificador de observacións de KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Perencana Observasi KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Pianificatore delle osservazioni di KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Plannen van waarnemingen in KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Planista obserwacji w KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Planeamento de Observações do KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Planejador de observação do KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Planiranje opazovanja v KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Observationsplanering i Kstars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">K Yıldızlar'ın Gözlem Planlayıcısı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Планування спостережень у KStars</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxObservation Planner of KStarsxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">KStars 的观测规划器</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">KStars 的觀測計劃器</caption>
      <image width="1600" height="900">https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kstars/kstars_planner.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kstars</binary>
  </provides>
  <custom>
    <value key="KDE::windows_store">https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9pprz2qhlxtg</value>
    <value key="KDE::google_play">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.kde.kstars.lite</value>
  </custom>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="3.5.7" date="2022-01-16"/>
    <release version="3.5.6" date="2021-11-10"/>
    <release version="3.5.5" date="2021-09-14"/>
    <release version="3.5.4" date="2021-07-03"/>
  </releases>
</component>
